#### EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

### Highlights

- 15+ years of Country- and B2B Sales Management and Business Development experience
- focus on Sales and Marketing of High-Tech capital goods
- studied Executive MBA
- M.Sc., Electr. Engineer, Industrial Automation & Control

#### Key Assets

#### **Business Management Skills.**

Long-term track of successful business development and B2B sales & marketing management of global corporations providing high-tech capital goods, solutions & services;

over 8 years Honeywell

- **Country Manager**
- industrial process control and homes & buildings automation/control;
- over 5 years Rockwell Automation

**Country Manager** 

- industrial automation systems, industrial software;

**Red Lion Controls** 3 vears

**CEE Sales Manager** 

- HMIs, panel meters and controllers;
  - **Sun Chemical**

**General Manager** 

2 years - printing ink business;

- **Siemens, Automation & Drives** 1 year
- **Solutions Sales Manager**
- Totally Integrated Automation & Totally Integrated Power solutions;

#### **\*** Business Development Experience.

I have practically introduced Honeywell, Rockwell Automation, Red Lion and Sun Chemical to Polish market and set-up a solid foundation for their current position.

Consequently I gained experience in developing and implementing strategies and business plans; restructured sales channels and maintained Key Accounts relationships. I have built sales and service organizations and led the sales teams to reach goals and to deliver financial results. I built and realized annual budgets typically aimed at profitable business growth.

#### Variety of Industrial Key Accounts.

I have done most of business with various industries, such as:

- power generation, water and wastewater, utilities,
- automotive and tyres [Daewoo, Fiat, Volkswagen, Tenneco, Goodyear, Michelin, Bridgestone],
- petrochemical and chemical [PKN Orlen, Lotos Group, large chemical synthesis plants, etc.],
- food & beverage [Nestle, Unilever, Coca Cola, Cadbury], pharma,
- consumer chemicals [ Procter&Gamble, Cussons, Henkel], packaging,
- building construction,
- glass, steel and metals processing plants, pulp & paper, printing, etc.

#### Drive, Education and Flexibility.

I have studied **Executive MBA** at the WEMBA program of Carlson School of Management, University of Minnesota and SGH, Warsaw. I speak **English** and **German** fluently, Polish is my mother tongue. I am flexible enough to relocate and eager to travel extensively for business purposes.

#### Range of Experience

- Projects, Services and Solutions sales for industry
- Sales Channels creation, restructuring and maintenance
- Customer relationship and Key Account management
- Sales and Service Team building
- Manufacturing Automation and Process Control architecture development

- Company management
- Company setup and development
- Strategy development and implementation
- o Business plan development and execution
- Budget development and implementation
- o Implementation of ISO 9000
- Business restructuring, Change Agent
- Product Management
- Project and Contract Management

### **PROFILE**

B2B sales and marketing management of technological capital goods;
International experience in sales of products, systems, services, projects and solutions to manufacturing, process and construction industries;

Tacknical process are to add to a size of a

Technical management and business strategy in the industrial automation industry;

PERSONAL DETAILS			
Date of birth:	June 13 <sup>th</sup> , 1957		
Gender:	Male		
Marital Status:	Married		
Address:	ul. Libijska 2H PL 03-977 Warsaw, Poland		
Contact Number:	+48 600 468478		
E- Mail Address:	marek_sinski@poczta.onet.pl		
Health Condition:	Excellent		
Languages:	English	German	Polish – native

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
Date	Organization	Job Title	
2003 – to date	MARK-S CONSULTING Warsaw, Poland	Distributor of Industrial Automation & Control Business Development Consultant own enterprise	
2008 – 2010	RED LION CONTROLS BV Amersfoort, The Netherlands a Spectris [UK] company	Regional Sales Manager Central & Eastern Europe	
2002 – 2003	SIEMENS LTD. Automation & Drives Div.	<ul><li>TIA/TIP Solutions Sales Manager</li><li>SP and CD Business Units Manager</li></ul>	
	Warsaw, Poland	CD and ET Business Units Manager	
1996 – 2001	ROCKWELL AUTOMATION LTD. Warsaw, Poland	Country Manager, Poland Board Member	
1994 – 1995	Sun Chemical Ltd. Warsaw, Poland	General Manager Board Member	
1993 – 1994	Mark-S Warsaw, Poland	Private trading enterprise Owner	
1984 – 1992	HONEYWELL AUSTRIA GES.M.B.H.	Country Manager, Poland	
	Warsaw Branch, Poland	Honeywell Sales Manager at Polymark Ltd., Honeywell's excl. distributor	
1983 – 1984	METRONEX LTD., Foreign Trade Company, Warsaw, Poland	Technical and Commercial Advisor	
1981 – 1983	Warszawa Iron-Steel Works Warsaw, Poland	Control Instrumentation Engineer	
1980 – 1981	KATOWICE IRON-STEEL WORKS (act. Mittal Steel) Dąbrowa Górnicza, Poland	Control Instrumentation Engineer	

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE AND SKILLS		
Organization:	Mark-S Consulting, Warsaw, Poland	
Industry:	Industrial Automation & Control distribution; Business consulting	
Period:	2003 – to date	
Position:	Distributor and VAR of Industrial Automation and Control Business Development Consultant; own business	

#### Job Description:

Distribution in Poland of industrial automation, control and measurement products, systems, services and solutions:

**Red Lion** – HMIs (Operator Panels), Panel Meters and Controllers **Microscan** – Precision Data Acquisition and Control Solutions

Machine Vision Systems and Barcode Readers and Scanners

**Dimetix** – Laser Distance Measurement

Business consulting: business start-up, development and/or reengineering. Managerial services.

Organization:	RED LION CONTROLS BV, Amersfoort, The Netherlands a Spectris company	
Industry:	Industrial Automation & Control	
Period:	Feb. 2008 – Aug. 2010	
Position:	Regional Sales Manager Central & Eastern Europe	

#### Job Description:

To develop company sales in Poland, Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary and Ukraine, Baltic states, Romania, Bulgaria and ex-Yugoslavia states.

Jan.- Aug. 2010 sales **growth 60%** over 2009. 2009 sales **growth 12%** over 2008.

Development of sales channels – selection, recruitment and setup of distributors, building of relations with the Key Accounts: OEMs, System Integrators and Panel Builders. "Brand label" projects.

Product marketing – identify proper applications, present competitive advantages, pricing policy. Increase of company potential through initiatives to takeover of complimentary companies from CEE region.

Organization:	SIEMENS LTD., AUTOMATION & DRIVES DIV., Warsaw, Poland		
Industry:	Manufacturing automation and process control		
Period:	Jul.2002 – Feb.2003		
Position:	TIA/TIP Solutions Sales Manager     SP and CD Business Units Manager		

#### Job Description:

Launch and development of a new A&D business, management of the sales team focused on the solution projects based on the *Totally Integrated Automation*® and *Totally Integrated Power*® platforms offered for the public buildings market as well as the automotive, petro- and chemical, glass, pharmaceutical and food&beverage industries. P&L responsibility.

Product marketing of SP – Solution Process Industries Business Unit + continued CD product marketing.

Period:	Mar. 2002 – Jun.2002	
Position:	CD and ET Business Units Manager	

#### Job Description:

Product marketing and restructuring of two business units: CD – Control Devices (low voltage control and power distribution devices, power switchboards) and ET – Electrotechnical Products. P&L responsibility.

ROCKWELL AUTOMATION LTD., Warsaw, Poland	
Automation Systems and Industrial Control Products business.	
1996 – 2001	
Country Manager Poland; Board Member	
1	

#### Job Description:

Brands: Allen-Bradley®, Rockwell Software® and Reliance Electric®.

Highlights: CAGR [FY96-FY01]: 50% growth scored.

One of the lowest Cost-to-Sell rates in RA Europe.

ISO9001 Certificate issued March 2001.

*Duties:* Business Plan prepared and presented to HQ in order to register Polish organization as the legal entity. Set-up of the newly formed company.

New accounts developed. Support to the Global- and local Key Accounts implemented.

Development of sales, technical service support and trainings activity.

Initiated sales of services and small-to-medium (100k€...3M€) automation projects.

Coordination and support for international projects/programs, ex.: *Bridgestone/Firestone, Daewoo, Fiat, Goodyear, Lucchini, Michelin, Nestle, P&G, Unilever,* etc.

Developed a new strategy for distribution channels, channels restructured and the strategy successfully implemented. Other marketing activities: introduction of new products and technologies to the market, monitored competition, fairs and tradeshows, etc.

Budget development. P&L responsibility, in particular to achieve Sales, GM, Cost-to-Sales and Operating Profit as planed.

Organization:	Sun Chemical Ltd., Warsaw, Poland	
Industry:	Printing ink business	
Period:	1994 – 1995	
Position:	General Manager, Board Member	

#### Job Description:

Highlight: achieved sales of 3,0 Mio. DM at 4,0% Net Profit during first FY of the Company operation. Duties: Company foundation and start-up. Facilities selection, staff recruitment, overall organization. Market positioning and development. Marketing study, accounts identification, contacts, sales and consequent customer service performed. Development strategy worked-out, distribution network established. P&L responsibility. Sales, profit and market share drastically grown.

Organization:	MARK-S, Warsaw, Poland		
Industry:	Consumer electronics distribution		
Period:	1993 – 1994		
Position:	Private trading enterprise, Owner		
Job Description:			
Import and distribution of consumer electronic equipment and compact cameras.			

Honeywell Austria Ges.m.b.H.
Industrial process control and homes and building automation business.
1989 – 1992
Country Manager Poland

#### Job Description:

Highlight: tenfold sales growth over 8 years (from 500k\$ up to 5 M\$). Duties started with the setup and development of the Branch followed by:

- Business Development Management: P&L responsibility, budgeting. Business strategy and expansion on Polish market, investment and development plans. Recruitment and management of the sales team. Management and coordination of the complete Honeywell sales program in Poland as well as third country projects. Development and maintenance of Key Accounts contacts; organization, development and handling of the distribution chain. Financial negotiations, financing solutions.
- Sales & Marketing: due to focused activities Industrial Automation Systems Div. (Distributed Control Systems TDC 3000) achieved leadership position on Polish market with over 40% market share supported by healthy growth of field instrumentation sales. Top 3 position on Homes & Buildings Control market. Marketing supported by market and competition analyses, fairs, seminars, presentations, feasibility studies, technical and commercial consulting.

Period:	1984 – 1989
Position:	Honeywell Sales Manager at Polymark Ltd., a Honeywell's exclusive distributor

#### Job Description:

Sold instrumentation and systems of the following Honeywell Inc. divisions: *Industrial Automation & Control, Homes and Buildings Automation & Control* as well as supplementary equipment.

Managed and coordinated the complete range of Honeywell products and systems sales in Poland. Created applications and produced feasibility studies. Provided technical and commercial consulting. Marketing: presentations and translations at tradeshows, exhibitions, fairs, seminars.

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE			
Date	Event / Conference		City, Country
2008 - 2010	Red Lion business		Central & Eastern Europe region see above
2002 – 2003	Siemens Quarterly and Annual Business Reviews		Marbella, Spain Nürnberg and Karlsruhe, Germany
1996 – 2001	Rockwell Automation Business Reviews and Management Meetings		Austria, Belgium, Germany, UK
	International Projects & Support Programs, examples:	Daewoo	South Korea
		Bridgestone	Japan
		Procter&Gamble Goodyear	United States
		Michelin	France

FORMAL EDUCATION				
Date	Institution	Qualification Gained		
2001 – 2003	WEMBA – Carlson School of Management - University of Minnesota, US and SGH, Warsaw, Poland	Executive MBA program		
1975 – 1980	SILESIAN TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY Gliwice, Poland Control Engineering and Computer Science Faculty	Master of Science, Industrial Automation and Control Engineering		

ADDITIONAL TRAINING				
Date	Institution	Skill Area		
2002	Siemens A&D	Change Management		
1996 – 2000	Rockwell Automation Internal courses	Business-to-business selling skills		
		Effective Leadership		
		Project Management		
		Basic Finance		
1984 – 1985	Central School of Planning and Statistics [act. SGH], Warsaw, Poland	Graduate Degree in Foreign Trade		

### **COMPUTER LITERACY**

Proficient in all MS Office Tools and Lotus Notes

CRM: SalesForce.com

### HOBBIES

Skiing, Windsurfing, English and American literature

REFERENCES				
	Available on request			

I hereby declare my consent to use my personal data for recruitment process related purposes (according to the Act on protection of Personal Data of August 29, 1997, published in Journal of Laws 133, item 883).

Wyrażam zgodę na przetwarzanie moich danych osobowych dla potrzeb niezbędnych do realizacji procesu rekrutacji (zgodnie z Ustawą o Ochronie Danych Osobowych z dnia 29.08.1997, Dz.U.133 poz.883).